Guide to the Elizabeth Bishop Papers, circa 1880-2023 (bulk 1929-1979)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES II. PROFESSIONAL CORRESPONDENCE, CONTRACTS, FINANCIAL STATEMENTS
  - Honorary degree: Brown University, 1972; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Brown University, 1972; (original) (Folder 97.2)
  - Honorary degree: Dalhousie University, 1979; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Dalhousie University, 1979; (original) (Folder 107.8 (Oversize))
  - Honorary degree: Princeton University, 1979; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Princeton University, 1979; (original) (Folder 107.6 (Oversize))
  - Honorary degree: Rutgers University, 1972; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Rutgers University, 1972; (original) (Folder 107.7 (Oversize))
  - Honorary degree: Smith College, 1968; (reduced size copy) (Folder 40.10)
  - Honorary degree: Smith College, 1968; (original) (Folder 97.1)
  - Miscellaneous materials relating to honorary degrees, 1968-1979; (Citations, letters, 1 letter fr. Bishop, copies of diplomas) (Folder 40.10)
  - Houghton Mifflin, 1946-1979; (3 letters) (Folder 41.1)
  - Houghton Mifflin (Olney, Austin), 1954-1957; (31 letters) (Folder 41.2)
  - Houghton Mifflin Poetry Awards, 1945; 3 letters, 1 telegram) (Folder 41.3)
  - Houghton Mifflin — See also Contracts, Folder 44.7
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1961-1973; (20 letters, 5 ccs by E. Bishop) (Folder 41.4)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1974; (2 letters) (Folder 123.5)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1974-1976; (13 letters, 3 mailgrams) (Folder 41.5)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1977; (32 letters, 1 mailgram, 5 ccs by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 41.6)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1978 Jan-Apr; (26 letters, 1 mailgram, 1 contract, 17 ccs by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 41.7)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1978 Jun-Sep; (18 letters, 1 postcard, 1 mailgram, 3 ccs by E.B) (Folder 41.8)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1978 Oct-Dec; (19 letters, 3 ccs by Elizabeth Bishop, 1 mailgram) (Folder 41.9)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1979 Jan-Mar; (13 letters, 5 ccs by E. Bishop) (Folder 42.1)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1979 Apr-Jul; (16 letters, 11 ccs by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 42.2)
  - Invitations to read/teach, 1979 Aug-Sep; (12 letters) (Folder 42.3)
  - Library of Congress Consultantship, 1949-1978; (5 letters, enclosures, 1 cc by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 42. 4)
  - Amy Lowell Scholarship, 1957-1971; (2 letters, 3 ccs by Elizabeth Bishop) (Folder 42.5)
  - Amy Lowell Fellowship, approximately 1978; (2 draft letters) (Folder 123.6)
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1974-1975; (2 letters) (Folder 42.6)
  - National Book Award, 1970, (1 letter, 6 telegrams, remarks of R. Lowell and I. B. Singer, 1 article) (Folder 42.7)
  - National Book Award, 1973, 1972-1973; (Miscellaneous lists, memos, correspondence) (Folder 42.8)
  - National Book Award, 1973, 1978; (Miscellaneous correspondence and memos) (Folder 42.9)
  - National Book Awards, 1979; (Miscellaneous correspondence and memos) (Folder 42.10)
  - National Book Awards, 1978-1979; (Miscellaneous lists and correspondence) (Folder 42.11)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1954; (3 letters, l letter drafted by E. Bishop, citation) (Folder 42.12)
  - The New York Times, 1965; (1 letter, 7 telegrams, 1 statement, 1 receipt) (Folder 42.14)
  - The New Yorker, 1969-1982; (17 letters, 2 cc by E. Bishop) (Folder 42.15)
  - The New Yorker — See also Contracts, Folder 44.9
  - Notable American Women, 1977; (1 letter, 1 memo, miscellaneous lists) (Folder 42.16)
  - Order of Rio Branco — correspondence, etc., 1971-1972; (2 letters, enclosures) (Folder 43.1)
  - Order of Rio Branco — citation, 1971 (Folder 106.1)
  - Order of Rio Branco — medal, 1971 (Box 110)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, Alpha of Massachusetts at Harvard University, 1972; (membership certificate) (Folder 43.2)
  - Poetry Magazine, 1963; (1 letter, 1 contract) (Folder 43.3)
  - Pomegranate Press (Stephen M. Savage), 1972; (1 letter) (Folder 127.3)
  - Pulitzer Prize, 1956; (1 letter, 6 telegrams) (Folder 43.4)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1966-1969; (13 letters, grant applications, 5 cc by E. Bishop) (Folder 43.5)
  - Rotterdam Arts Foundation, 1975-1976; (5 letters, 1 booklet) (Folder 123.7)
  - Sable Island, 1951; (4 letters, enclosures) (Folder 43.6)
  - St. Botolph Club Arts Award, 1975; (1 letter) (Folder 43.7)
  - Shelley Memorial Award, 1952; (2 letters, enclosures) (Folder 43.8)
  - Solicitation of personal papers, 1963-1979; (8 letters, 3 drafts by Bishop, 1 enclosure) (Folder 43.9)
  - Elizabeth Spires, 1976; (5 letters (photocopies)) (Folder 43.10)
  - Time-Life, 1961; (12 letters, 2 telegrams, 7 cc by Bishop, related correspondence From Carl Brandt) (Folder 43.11)
  - University of Connecticut — request for a recommendation, 1974 Oct 2; (1 letter) (Folder 123.8)
  - War Manpower Commission, 1943; (Employment papers) (Folder 43.12)
  - Washington Post, 1977; (1 letter) (Folder 43.13)
  - White House, 1961-1970; (3 letters) (Folder 43.14)
  - Wright, Gerald A., 1970-1971; (3 letters, invoices) (Folder 43.15)
  - Yellin, Herb (Lord John Press), 1978-1979; (3 letters, 1 cc by E. Bishop) (Folder 43.16)
  - Yellin, Herb (Lord John Press), 1979, 2003; (9 letters, 2 photocopies, 1 check, 1 water color painting) (Folder 127.8 - 127.11)
    Material related to the publication of the 1979 broadside of the poem "North Haven." Correspondents include Yellin, Bishop, Joelle Biele and the artist Kit Barker.
  - Miscellaneous professional correspondence, A – L, 1968-1979; (20 letters, 13 cc by E. Bishop) (Folder 43.17)
  - Miscellaneous professional correspondence, M – Z, 1956-1979; (18 letters, 7 cc by E. Bishop) (Folder 43.18)
  - Financial statements, 1959-1973; (Miscellaneous items) (Folder 43.19)
  - Contract - Alice Brandt, 1956; (1 contract) (Folder 44.1)
  - Contract - Chatto and Windus, 1966; (1 contract) (Folder 44.2)
  - Contract - Chatto and Windus, 1970; (2 contracts, 1 letter) (Folder 123.9)
  - Contracts - Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, 1965-1967, undated; (2 contracts) (Folder 44.3)
  - Contracts - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1967-1976, undated; (2 contracts, miscellaneous correspondence) (Folder 44.4)
  - Contracts - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 1968; (1 contract, miscellaneous notes and correspondence) (Folder 123.10)
  - Contract - Hearst Corp. and Farrar, Straus and Cudahy, undated; (1 contract) (Folder 44.5)
  - Contract - A.M. Heath, 1958; (1 contract, 1 copy) (Folder 44.6)
  - Contract - Houghton-Mifflin, 1945; (1 contract) (Folder 44.7)
  - Contract - Limes Verlag, 1961; (1 contract) (Folder 44.8)
  - Contracts - The New Yorker, 1957-1977; (6 contracts) (Folder 44.9)
  - Contract - The New Yorker, 1976 Aug 4; (1 contract) (Folder 123.11)
  - Contract - Rizzoli Editore, 1970; (1 contract) (Folder 44.10)
- SERIES III. PERSONAL FINANCIAL AND LEGAL DOCUMENTS
  - Casa Mariana, Ouro Preto — General (Folder 123.15)
  - Casa Mariana, Ouro Preto — Correspondence, etc. relating to sale, 1971-1976, undated (Folder 123.16)
  - Casa Mariana, Ouro Preto — Advertisements, approximately 1976 (Folder 124.1)
  - Casa Mariana, Ouro Preto — Transport of house contents to Boston, 1974 (Folder 124.2)
  - Casa Mariana, Ouro Preto — Classified ad for rental or sale in the New York Review of Books, undated (Folder 42.13)
  - Lewis Wharf, Boston — General, 1973-1978, undated (Folder 123.12)
  - Lewis Wharf, Boston — Advertisements and specifications (Folder 123.13)
  - Lewis Wharf, Boston — Remodeling (Folder 123.14)
  - Lewis Wharf, Boston — Plans (Folder 107.9 (Oversize))
  - Personal medical bills, 1953-1954, undated; (12 receipts; 1 list of medications) (Folder 44.11)
  - Hotel bills — Sea View, Don Carlos, Ambassade, and Normandy, 1932, 1950, 1966, 1972; (1 receipt) (Folder 44.12)
  - Temporary Brazilian visas, 1957, 1964, 1967; (3 items) (Folder 44.13)
  - Will of Elizabeth Bishop, 1972; (1 notebook) (Folder 44.14)
  - Will of Elizabeth Bishop, 1973 (Folder 122.2)
  - Will of Elizabeth Bishop — Letter to Alice Methfessel, 1978 May 25; (1 TLS) (Folder 122.3)
  - Mount Hope Cemetery, Worcester, MA — Plot care agreement, blank, 1941 (Folder 122.4)
  - Appraisal of Bishop's Papers, 1978-1980 (Folder 122.19)
  - Miscellaneous bank documents, 1972-1974 (Folder 124.5)
  - Miscellaneous legal and financial documents, 1961-1979, undated (Folder 124.6)
  - Receipts — Brazil, 1966 (Folder 124.7-124.9)
  - Receipts — Brazil, 1968-1970 (Folder 124.10)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1970; (3 receipts) (Folder 115.18)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, ca, 1974 (Folder 124.11)
- SERIES IV. PROSE
  - Published prose
    - The Baptism, [1937]; (TS, 2 drafts, 14 p.) (Folder 45.1)
    - In Prison, [1938]; (TS, 1 draft, 14 p.) (Folder 45.2)
    - Gregorio Valdes, 1879-1939, (TS, 2 drafts, 21 p.) (Folder 45.3)
    - Miss Moore and the Delight of Imitation, [1942]; (MS, TS, 5 drafts, outline, 39 p.) (Folder 45. 4)
    - The Farmer's Children, [1948]; (TS, 2 drafts, 27 p.) (Folder 45.5)
    - Gwendolyn, [1953]; (TS, 3 drafts, fragment, notes, working proof, 42 p.) (Folder 45.6)
    - [Bishop's manuscript translation of the diary located in 72B.4a-72B.4b and 73.1]
    - The Diary of "Helena Morley." Galley proofs of Houghton, Mifflin, Cudahy edition, [c1957] (Folder 46.1-46.3)
    - The Diary of "Helena Morley." Foreword (to The Ecco Press edition), [1977]; (TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 46.4)
    - The Diary of "Helena Morley." Drawing. Book Jacket [designed by Cyntha Krupat, daughter of Frani Muser], [1977]; (1 p.) (Folder 46.5)
    - Brazil. Chapter outline, reading notes, early drafts, chapter corrections, [1960-1962]; (TS, MS, 73 p.) (Folder 47.1)
    - Brazil. Draft, Chapter I, [1960-1962]; (TS, MS, 17 p.) (Folder 47.2)
    - Brazil. Drafts, Chapter II, [1960-1962]; (TS, MS, 16 p.) (Folder 47.3)
    - Brazil. Drafts, Chapter III, [1960-1962]; (TS, MS, 14 p.) (Folder 47. 4)
    - Brazil. Drafts, Chapter IV, [1960-1962]; (TS, 10 p.) (Folder 47.5)
    - [No Chapter V]
    - Brazil. Draft Chapter VI, [1960-1962]; (TS, 12 p.) (Folder 47.6)
    - Brazil. Draft Chapter VII, [1960-1962]; (TS, 18 p.) (Folder 47.7)
    - Brazil. Draft Chapter VIII, [1960-1962]; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 47.8)
    - Brazil. Draft Chapter IX, [1960-1962]; (TS, 16 p.) (Folder 47.9)
    - Brazil. Draft Chapter X, [1960-1962]; (TS, 7 p.) (Folder 47.10)
    - Brazil. Chapter I, (Proofs) (Folder 48.1)
    - Brazil. Chapter II, (Proofs) (Folder 48.2)
    - Brazil. Chapter III, (Proofs) (Folder 48.3)
    - Brazil. Chapter IV, (Proofs) (Folder 48. 4)
    - Brazil. Chapter V, (Proofs) (Folder 48.5)
    - Brazil. Chapter VI, (Proofs) (Folder 48.6)
    - Brazil. Chapter VII, (Proofs) (Folder 48.7)
    - Brazil. Chapter VIII, (Proofs) (Folder 48.8)
    - Brazil. Chapter IX, (Proofs) (Folder 48.9)
    - Brazil. Chapter X, (Proofs) (Folder 48.10)
    - A Trip to Vigia, [approximately 1960]; (TS, MS, 2 drafts, fragments, 19 p.) (Folder 52.1)
    - Trollope in Washington, [1961]; (TS, draft fragment, 1 p.) (Folder 49.1)
    - Review: A Sentimental Tribute, A Marianne Moore Reader, [1962]; (TS, 2 drafts, 14 p.) (Folder 49.2)
    - A Hen (story by Clarice Lispector) translated by E. Bishop, [Summer 1964]; (TS, 1 draft, 4 p.) (Folder 49.3)
    - Marmosets, translated by E. Bishop, [Summer 1964]; (TS, 1 draft, 4 p.) (Folder 49. 4)
    - The Smallest Woman in the World (by Clarice Lispector) translated by E. Bishop, [Summer 1964]; (TS, 1 draft, 8 p.) (Folder 49.5)
    - Milledgeville Unvisited, [approximately 1964]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 49.6)
    - On the Railroad Named Delight, [1965]; (TS, miscellaneous drafts, 54 p.) (Folder 49.7)
    - Complaining Creatures (Rainy Season; Sub-Tropics), [1967]; (TS, miscellaneous drafts, 8 p.) (Folder 49.8)
    - Introduction (Anthology of Brazilian Poetry), [1972]; (TS, 4 drafts, 23 p.) (Folder 49.9)
    - A Brief Reminiscence and A Brief Tribute, [1974]; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 49.10)
    - The Work! A Conversation with E. Bishop by George Starbuck, 1977; (1 draft with revisions, 27 p.) (Folder 49.11)
    - The Country Mouse, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 17 p.) (Folder 52.2)
    - [Efforts of Affection:] An Account of Marianne Moore, undated; (TS, 3 drafts, notes, 77 p.) (Folder 52.3)
    - [Memories of] Uncle Neddy, [1975]; (TS, 4 drafts, mss notes, 2 photocopies) (Folder 52.4)
    - Mercedes Hospital, undated; (MS, TS, 1 draft, notes, 22 p.) (Folder 52.5)
    - Primer Class, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 15 p.) (Folder 52.6)
    - To the Botequim and Back, [approximately 1970]; (TS, 1 draft, typescript) (Folder 52.7)
    - The U.S.A. School of Writing [rejected by New Yorker, 10/19/56], undated; (TS, 4 drafts, 52 p.) (Folder 52.8)
    - Was It In His Hand?, undated; (MS, TS, 2 drafts, 13 p.) (Folder 52.9)
  - Unpublished prose
    - Aristophanes’ The Birds [partial translation], [1933-1934]; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 53.1)
      Aristophanes’ The Birds — See also Folder 72.4
    - Mechanics of Pretense: Remarks on W. H. Auden, [approximately 1937]; (MS, 1 draft, 5 p.) (Folder 53.2)
    - 5/10,000 Islands, [approximately 1942]; (TS, 1 draft, 9 p.) (Folder 53.3)
    - The Water- (River) Rat [rejected by New Yorker, 10/22/48], [approximately 1948?]; (TS, 2 drafts, 12 p.) (Folder 53.4)
    - A New Capital, Aldous Huxley, and Some Indians, 1959 Sep; (TS, 1 draft, 47 p.) (Folder 53.5)
    - [Autobiographical Sketch], 1961; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 53.6)
    - The Procession of St. George, [approximately 1963]; (TS, 2 drafts, fragments, 7 p.) (Folder 53.7)
    - Gallery Note for Wesley Wehr, 1967 Mar; (TS, 3 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 53.8)
    - [Untitled Essay], [1968]; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 53.9)
    - The Fairy Toll-Taker, [1968]; (TS, fragment, 1 p.) (Folder 53.10)
    - Three American Poets, [1968-1969]; (TS, 1 draft, 7 p.) (Folder 53.11)
    - Transcript: Discussion with Kathleen Cleaver, 1969; (TS, 23 p., 1 TLS (photocopy) to K. Cleaver fr. Roxanne Cumming) (Folder 53.12)
    - Baby with a Broken Toe: An Interview (A Play), 1969; (TS, 1 draft, 7 p.) (Folder 53.13)
    - [Poetry Reviews and Notes], [approximately 1970]; (TS, 6 p.) (Folder 53.14)
    - Another American, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 6 p.) (Folder 53.15)
    - El Caracol, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 53.16)
    - [Circus Essay], undated; (MS, fragment, 2 p.) (Folder 53.17)
    - The Deadly Sandpile, undated; (MS, 1 draft, 1 fragment, 5 p.) (Folder 53.18)
    - Eula Wiggle, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 22 p.) (Folder 53.19)
    - Farewell Teresa, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.1)
    - Grand Opening, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.2)
    - Homesickness, undated; (TS, MS, 2 drafts) (Folder 54.3)
    - In the Money (Unsuperstitious Dr. Williams?), undated; (MS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 54.4)
    - The Last Waltz, Ch. 73, undated; (MS, 1 p. fragment) (Folder 54.5)
    - [Lowell Reminiscences], undated; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 54.6)
    - Lulu and His Wife, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, fragments, 6 p.) (Folder 54.7)
    - May Day, undated; (TS, 3 drafts, 16 p.) (Folder 54.8)
    - Mrs. Sullivan Downstairs, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 8 p. [there is no p. 6]) (Folder 54.9)
    - The New Guide of the Conversation, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.10)
    - On the Way, undated; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 54.11)
    - Remarks on Translation -of Poetry, Mostly, undated; (MS notes, 2 p. TS, 2 p.) (Folder 54.12)
    - [Reminiscences of Great Village], undated; (MS, TS, 2 drafts, 39 p.) (Folder 54.13)
    - Review: Pantomime, A Journal of Remembrance, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.14)
    - Review: Come Hither, undated; (TS, 6 drafts, 31 p.) (Folder 54.15)
    - Review: Clock Ticks, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 54.16)
    - Review: The Devil to Pay in the Backlands, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.17)
    - Review: Emily Dickinson's Letters to Dr. and Mrs Josiah Gilbert Holland., undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.18)
    - Review: The Riddle of Emily Dickinson, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.19)
    - Review: Letters Home by Sylvia Plath, undated; (TS, 2 p.) (Folder 54.20)
    - Review: The Baroque Style in Prose, undated; (MS, TS, 3 p.) (Folder 54.21)
    - Suicide of a Moderate Dictator, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 54.22)
    - [Table of contents for unpublished book of prose], undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 54.23)
    - The Tempest; Reach Me a ... Fancy, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 fragments, 16 p.) (Folder 55.1)
    - [Trip on the Amazon: description trip of February 1960], undated; (TS, 1 draft, 9 p.) (Folder 55.2)
    - A Trip on the Rio São Francisco, undated; (Miscellaneous drafts) (Folder 55.3)
    - A Trip on the Rio São Francisco - Later draft, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 8 p.) (Folder 55.4)
    - True Confessions, undated; (TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 55. 5)
    - Under Glass, undated; (MS, 1 draft, fragments, 2 p.) (Folder 55.6)
    - An Unsuccessful Attempt (An Uncomfortable Trip?), undated; (TS, 1 draft, 3 p.) (Folder 55.7)
    - Waiting for the Mail in Florida, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 9 p.) (Folder 55.8)
- SERIES V. POETRY
  - Published poetry
    - The Wave, [1929 Apr]; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 56.1)
    - The Flood, [1933 Feb]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 56.2)
    - Three Sonnets for Eyes, [1933 Nov]; (TS, 1 draft, fragment, 3 p.) (Folder 56.3)
    - Valentine I, II, [1934 Feb]; (MS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 56.4)
    - Argument, [1947 Jan-Feb]; (MS, TS, 3 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 56.5)
    - Varick Street, [1947 Feb?]; (MS, TS, 6 drafts, 9 p.) (Folder 56.6)
    - At the Fish-Houses, [1947 Aug]; (MS, TS, 6 drafts, 13 p.) (Folder 56.7)
    - To Marianne Moore [For M. M.] [Invitation to Marianne Moore], [1948 Spring]; (MS, 4 drafts, 9 p.) (Folder 56.8)
    - Over 2,000 Illustrations and a Complete Concordance, [1948 Jun]; (MS, TS, 6 drafts, 16 p.) (Folder 56.9)
    - A Summer's Dream, [1948 Jul]; (TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 56.10)
      [second page may be unrelated]
    - The Bight (On My Birthday), [1949 Feb]; (MS, TS, 4 drafts 5 p.) (Folder 56.11)
    - Cape Breton, [1949 Jun]; (MS, TS, 5 drafts, early drafts, fragment, 8 p.) (Folder 56.12)
    - Poems (by Max Jacob, translated by E. Bishop), [1950 May]; (TS, 11 p.) (Folder 56.13)
    - Insomnia, [1951 Jun]; (MS, 1 draft, 2 p) (Folder 57.1)
    - View of the Capitol from the Library of Congress, [1951 Jul]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 57.2)
    - A Cold Spring, [1952 May]; (MS, TS, 8 drafts, fragments, 14 p.) (Folder 57.3)
    - Arrival at Santos, [1952 Jun]; (MS, TS, 5 drafts fragments, 7 p.) (Folder 57.4)
    - The Mountain, [1952 Oct]; (MS, TS, 9 drafts, 11 p.) (Folder 57.5)
    - The Shampoo, [1955 Jul]; (MS, TS, 6 drafts, 10 p.) (Folder 57.6)
    - The Shampoo, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 113.15)
    - Filling Station (Station #2), [1955 Dec]; (TS, 1 draft, photocopy of column in The New Yorker with mss. corrections, 2 pp.) (Folder 57.7)
    - Questions of Travel, [1956 Jan]; (MS, TS, 7 drafts, 13 p.) (Folder 57.8)
    - Squatter's Children, [1956 Apr]; (TS, 6 drafts, fragment, 9 p.) (Folder 57.9)
    - Manuelzinho, [1956 May]; (TS, 6 drafts, 14 p.) (Folder 57.10)
    - Sestina, [1956 Sep]; (TS, 4 drafts, 4 p. [with TS sent by Elizabeth Bishop to James Merrill, 1 p.]) (Folder 57.11)
    - St. Elizabeth's (1950) [Visits to St. Elizabeth's], [1957 Spring]; (MS, 1 draft, 4 p. [with mimeograph sent by Elizabeth Bishop sent to James Merrill, 2 p.]) (Folder 57.12)
    - The Owl's Nest [The Armadillo], [1957 Jun]; (TS, 3 drafts, 3 p.) (Folder 57.13)
    - The Armadillo, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 113.13)
    - Sunday, 4 A.M., [1958 Sep]; (TS, 4 drafts, 4 p.) (Folder 57.14)
    - Sunday, 4 A.M. (one draft signed and dated), 1956 Oct 7, undated; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 113.16)
    - January First, 1502 [Brazil, January 1, 1502], [1960 Jan]; (TS, 8 drafts, 13 p.) (Folder 57.15)
    - The River-Man, [1960 Apr]; (TS, 6 drafts, fragments, 25 p.) (Folder 57.16)
    - Electrical Storm, [1960 May]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 58.1)
    - Electrical Storm, 1977 Oct 1; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 127.7)
    - Song for [a] the Rainy Season, [1956], [1960 Oct]; (TS draft with mss corrections from The New Yorker) (Folder 58.2)
    - Key West. "A Norther" (A Norther -- Key West) (also, A Bitter Day --Key West), [1962 Jan]; (MS, TS, 2 drafts 2 p.) (Folder 58.3)
    - First Death in Nova Scotia, [1962 Mar]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 58.4)
    - First Death in Nova Scotia, undated; (TS, 1 p.) (Folder 113.14)
    - Twelfth Morning; Or What You Will [for early drafts, see Real Estate Development - 6 a.m. in 67.5], [1964 Apr]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 58.5)
    - The Burglar of Babylon, [1964 Nov]; (TS, 7 drafts, fragment, 27 p.) (Folder 58.6)
    - On the Railroad Named Delight (Sambas of 1965), [1965 Mar]; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 58.7)
    - Under the Window. Ouro Prêto, [1966 Dec]; (TS, 3 drafts fragment, p.) (Folder 58.8)
    - Going to the Bakery (Rio de Janeiro), [1968 Mar]; (TS, 2 drafts, 2 p.) (Folder 58.9)
    - Corrections for Collected Poems of E. Bishop [i.e., Complete Poems, 1969], (TS, 1 draft, 20 p.) (Folder 58.10)
    - House Guest, [1968 Dec]; (TS, 4 drafts, 5 p.) (Folder 58.11)
    - The Table (by Carlos Drummond de Andrade, translated by E. Bishop), [1969 Jan]; (MS, TS, 3 drafts, fragment, galleys, 30 p.) (Folder 58.12)
    - Thank-You Note, [1969 Spring]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 58.13)
    - In the Waiting Room, [1971 Jul]; (TS, 6 drafts, 13 p.) (Folder 58.14)
    - Cemetery of Childhood (by Joaquim Cardozo, translated by E. Bishop), [1971 Nov]; (TS, 1 draft, 2 p.) (Folder 58.15)
    - Crusoe in England - Early drafts, [1971 Nov]; (TS, drafts, fragments, 21 p.) (Folder 58.16)
    - Crusoe in England, [1971 Nov]; (TS, 4 drafts, 10 p.) (Folder 58.17)
    - Sonnet of Intimacy (by Vinicius De Moraes, translated by E. Bishop), [1971 Nov]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 59.1)
    - Along Galeana Street; The Key of Water; The Page (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), [Summer 1972]; (MS, TS, 6 drafts, 8 p.) (Folder 59.2)
    - The Grove, [Summer 1972]; (MS, TS, 7 drafts, note, 18 p.) (Folder 59.3)
    - The Moose -Early drafts, [1972 Jul]; (MS, TS, misc. drafts) (Folder 59.4)
    - The Moose -Later drafts, [1972 Jul]; (MS,TS, misc. drafts) (Folder 59.5)
    - Night City, [1972 Sep]; (MS, TS, 14 drafts, fragment, 22 p.) (Folder 59.6)
    - Poem, [1972 Nov]; (TS, 10 drafts, mimeocopy (signed and dated) 17 p.) (Folder 59.7)
    - 12 O'Clock News, [1973 Mar]; (MS, TS, 4 drafts, 8 p.) (Folder 59.8)
    - Five Flights Up, [1974 Feb]; (MS, TS, 12 drafts, 12 p.) (Folder 59.9)
    - Objects and Appearances [Objects and Apparitions (For Joseph Cornell)] (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), [1974 Jun]; (MS, TS, 4 drafts) (Folder 59.10)
    - January First (by O. Paz, translated by E. Bishop), 1975 Jan; (TS, 3 draft, 5 p.) (Folder 59.11)
    - [The] End of March, [1975 Mar]; (TS, 11 drafts, fragment, 24 p.) (Folder 60.1)
    - One Art, [1976 Apr]; (MS, TS, 17 drafts, 17 p.) (Folder 60.2)
    - Geography Lesson [Geography III], [1976]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.; book jacket rendering, 1 p.) (Folder 60.3)
    - Santarem, [1978 Feb]; (TS, 16 drafts, fragments, galley, 36 p.) (Folder 60.4)
    - North Haven, [1978 Dec]; (TS, MS, miscellaneous drafts, 19 p.) (Folder 60.5)
    - Pink Dog, [approximately 1963]; (TS, 7 drafts, fragments, 10 p.) (Folder 60.6)
    - Sonnet, [undated]; (MS, TS, early drafts, 3 drafts, 9 p.) (Folder 60.7)
    - Pleasure Seas, 1939; (TS, 1 draft, 1p.) (Folder 60.8)
    - Foreign-Domestic, undated; (MS, TS, 2 drafts, photocopy of pub. poem, 3 p.) (Folder 60.9)
  - Unpublished poetry
    - I Introduce Penelope Gwin ...; Once on a Hill ..., [late ‘20s?]; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 64.1)
    - How To Detect A Moderate Rain, [1930-1934]; (TS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 64.2)
    - Good-Bye, [1931-1934]; (MS, 1 draft, 1 p.) (Folder 64.3)